Great job finishing this section on the related areas of project management I know we covered a lot
of information in this section.
So let's just hit the headlines again and have a good wrap up before we move into new material.
In the section we looked at the different components of an organization that are related to project
management.
We talked about project management of course and then we talked about program management and portfolio
management and how those three entities can work together can be all part of one another and how you
need to operate as a project manager in any one of those instances whether you're a solo project or
working inside of a program or you're part of a portfolio.
We talked about working with a PMO a project management office and how does that affect you as a project
manager and how you operate as a PM and your organization.
In this section we also discussed is that a project or is that an operation and I know you completed
an assignment where you were able to recognize projects or operations.
So that was really important to do.
We discussed OPM organizational project management and business strategy.
We talked about strategy and the vision of the organization's strategy what helps us achieve that vision.
How does OPM fit into that hierarchy.
I mean you have to understand the different project environments the environment you're operating in
affects how you get to manage the project the amount of authority that you have as the project manager.
And then you want to recognize those different environments even if you aren't working on those structures
because that will affect how you answer any exam question.
So you need to be aware of those for your exam or passing your PMP And then of course as I mentioned
in the coaching session know your terms if you know the terms you go through those flashcards that are
sprinkled throughout the scores know your terms that's going to help you answer the question if you
don't recognize the term.
You have no idea what it is and it's really tough to be able to understand what the question is asking.
All right.
Good job you are making great progress.
You're already through Section Six here.
Well let's go ahead and start.
Section 7 you can do it.
I have confidence in you.